According to our first look...
（大石(おおいし)）所見で見たかぎり―
ホトケは
喉をかきむしって死んでいます
...it seems like the victim clawed
at his throat with his own fingers.
それも 自分の爪で…
（入江(いりえ)）これは
真っ当な死に方じゃありませんよ
This is a very strange
way of killing oneself.
（大石）薬ですかね？
Was he on drugs?
I've never heard of a drug
that can make a person...
死んでしまうほど
喉をかきむしるように―
誘導できる薬物なんて
聞いたことありません
...claw at his throat till he dies.
Oishi-san!
（熊谷(くまがい)）大石さん！
（大石）うん？
What about this lumber?
（熊谷）この角材は？
多分 ホトケが
振り回したんじゃないかと思います
I think the victim swung it around.
We also saw several bruises
on Tomitake-san's body.
富竹(とみたけ)さんの体にも―
打撲傷を思わせる痕が
いくつか見られましたが…
He was attacked by
someone after the festival...
（大石）
祭りのあと 興宮(おきのみや)へ帰る途中―
ここで何者かに襲われた …か？
...on his way home
to Okinomiya, huh?
そういえば 鷹野(たかの)さん…
Speaking of which, Takano-san...
えっ？ おたくの看護婦さんの？
The nurse at your clinic?
I think she was
with Tomitake-san.
多分 富竹さんと
一緒だったと思うんです
熊ちゃん
署に在宅確認を取らせてください
Kuma-chan, please check with
the department if she was home.
Yes, sir.
（熊谷）了解ッス
（大石）ああ それと…
Oh, also...
（大石）県警に今夜 身元不明の
女性死体が出ていないかも―
Check with the local police...
...if any unidentified female
body has been found tonight.
確認取ってください
（熊谷）了解ッス
Yes, sir.
鷹野さんも
殺されているということですか？
Are you saying Takano-san
has also been killed?
さ～て どうでしょうねえ？
Well, I'm not sure.
ただ
彼女が見つからないとすると…
However, if she is not found,
then this will be the fifth year.
５年目ってことですよ
（入江）ええっ？
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)連続怪死事件
Hinamizawa's
serial mysterious deaths.
Also known as
"Oyashiro-sama's curse."
通称“オヤシロさまのたたり”が…
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 03: DOCUMENT 34
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（沙都子(さとこ)）
おーほっほっほっほっ！
全てのカギは
この注射器にありましてよ
The syringe has all
the hints to the mystery.
（圭一(けいいち)）ウウッ… やるな 沙都子！
You're pretty good.
（梨花(りか)）沙都子が本気なら―
If Satoko is serious, then I
have to become serious too.
ボクも
本気を出さないといけませんです
（ﾚﾅ）
よ～し レナも本気でいくからね！
Then I'm gonna get serious too.
（魅音(みおん)）アハハハッ！
よしよし 盛り上がってきたね
Good, good!
It's getting heated up!
（知恵(ちえ)）楽しそうなところ
ジャマして ごめんなさい
I'm sorry to interrupt
when you're having fun.
竜宮(りゅうぐう)さんに
お客さまが来ていますよ
Ryugu-san,
there's a visitor for you.
Okay.
（大石）
竜宮さんですか？ 竜宮礼奈(れいな)さん？
Are you Ryugu-san?
Reina Ryugu-san?
（ﾚﾅ）どちらさまですか？
Who are you?
Since my car has
air conditioning, let's talk in there.
私の車はエアコンが効いてますから
そっちで お話ししましょう
（ﾚﾅ）私に何の用ですか？
What do you want from me?
Do you know
anything about this man?
（大石）この男性のことで
ご存じのことがあったら―
教えてください
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
これ 富竹さん？
Isn't this Tomitake-san?
Then do you know this woman?
では
こちらの女性は分かりますか？
（ﾚﾅ）三四(みよ)さんです 鷹野三四さん
This is Miyo-san.
Miyo Takano-san.
When was the last
time you saw these two?
（大石）この２人に
最後に会ったのは いつですか？
綿流しのお祭りの夜に…
At the night of
the Cotton Drifting Festival.
Did something catch
your attention at that time?
そのとき 何か気になったこととか
ありませんか？
何でも結構です
Anything is fine.
富竹さんたちに
何か あったんですか？
Did something happen to them?
ハァ…
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
Oh, it's Rena-chan, right?
（鷹野）あら レナちゃんじゃない
（ﾚﾅ）あっ…
Miyo-san.
三四さん こんにちは
Hello.
It's rare that you're at the library.
珍しいわね
あなたが図書館にいるなんて
What brings you here?
三四さんこそ どうしたんですか？
ちょっと調べたいことがあってね
I wanted to research something.
The serial mysterious deaths?
連続怪死事件？
（鷹野）
聞いたことくらいあるでしょう？
I'm sure you've
heard about it, right?
Hinamizawa's
serial mysterious deaths.
雛見沢連続怪死事件のこと
Yes.
（ﾚﾅ）ハァ…
（鷹野）５年目の今年も あるわよ
It will definitely happen again
this year for the fifth time.
絶対に
（ﾚﾅ）アア…
You know about the belief
in Oyashiro-sama, don't you?
雛見沢のオヤシロさま信仰は
知ってるわよね？
（ﾚﾅ）あっ はい
Yes.
These serial mysterious deaths
are carried out by fanatics...
連続怪死事件は オヤシロさまを
崇拝する狂信的勢力が―
...that worship Oyashiro-sama
to show off his power.
オヤシロさまの力を
誇示するために起こしている…
That's my speculation.
…というのが 私の推理なんだけど
A fanatical organization?
狂信的勢力？
村の名前が
雛見沢に変わって以来―
Ever since the village's name
changed to Hinamizawa...
...many longtime Onigafuchi
Village customs have ceased.
鬼ヶ淵(おにがふち)村が長く続けてきた
さまざまな風習が途絶えている
I believe there's a group
trying to revive those customs...
それをよみがえらせ 再び
鬼ヶ淵の名に対する恐れを―
...and bring back fear
of the name Onigafuchi.
取り戻そうと思っている人たちが
いるんじゃないかって
For example, the three great
families of Hinamizawa.
（鷹野）例えば 雛見沢御三家とか
Demons gushing from Onigafuchi
Swamp attacked the village...
鬼ヶ淵沼より湧き出した鬼が
村を襲い
...and Oyashiro-sama couldn't
stand it, calming them down...
それを見かねたオヤシロさまが
鬼たちを鎮め
村に共存させるために
人の姿を与えた
...and giving them human
forms to coexist with the village.
Is that the legend
of Oyashiro-sama?
オヤシロさま伝説ですか？
What can you
derive from this legend?
レナちゃんは この神話から
何を読み取れるかしら？
あの… その…
Um, it's about
Oyashiro-sama, but...
オヤシロさまの話なんですけど…
（鷹野）なぁに？
What?
私 オヤシロさまに
会ったことがあるんです
I've met Oyashiro-sama before.
本当に？
（ﾚﾅ）あっ はい…
Really?
Yes.
私 小学校に上がる前までは
雛見沢に住んでいたんです
Before I entered grade school,
I lived in Hinamizawa.
But due to my mother's work,
I moved to Ibaraki...
それが 母の仕事の関係で
茨城に引っ越して
（ﾚﾅ）えっと…
Um...
“雛見沢を
離れてはならない”という―
You're saying that you broke
Oyashiro-sama's taboo...
オヤシロさまの
タブーを破ったということね？
...of not leaving
Hinamizawa, right?
Yes.
そうです　それで―
And then a lot of
bad things happened.
いろいろ悪いことが起こって
In desperation, I did bad things.
私も自暴自棄になって
悪いことをしたりしました
Because I wanted
to break myself...
自分を壊してしまいたいと思って
...at times I placed
a blade toward myself.
体に刃物を
突きつけたことがあったんです
When I cut
my wrist with a razor...
そのとき
手首をカミソリで切りつけたら…
...several maggots
came out mixed with blood.
血に交じって
無数のウジ虫が出てきたんです
Plus, in order not to come out...
しかも
そいつらは外へ あふれまいと―
...they tried
to go back in the wound.
傷口から再び 中へ戻っていこうと
ワラワラうごめいていたんです
I scratched it.
私 かきました
手首の傷をひっかいて
ほじくり出そうとしました
I clawed at the cut
and tried to dig them out.
It was very itchy.
それが…
それが とても かゆいんです！
（鷹野）レナちゃん
Rena-chan.
そんなときに現れたんです
オヤシロさまが
That's when
Oyashiro-sama appeared.
And Oyashiro-sama said there's
only one way for me to survive...
そして 言ったんです
“あなたが助かる方法は１つ
雛見沢に帰ること”
...and that is
to return to Hinamizawa.
（ﾚﾅ）
フフッ… 信じられませんよね？
It's unbelievable, isn't it?
私は信じる
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
I will believe it.
（鷹野）私の秘蔵のスクラップ
貸してあげる
This is my treasured scrapbook.
I'll lend it to you.
あなたなら バカにしないで―
I feel you won't make fun of it,
and you'll take it seriously.
ちゃんと
読んでくれそうな気がするし
Let me hear what you think.
感想を聞かせて
ひょっとすると レナちゃんにしか
分からないことなのかもしれない
There might be things that
only you can understand.
Also, keep the scrapbook
and my research a secret.
あと このスクラップ帳と
私が そういう研究しているのは…
ナイショよ
A secret?
ナイショですか？
Because if those guys find
out that I'm researching this...
だって こんな研究をしているのが
連中に知られたら―
...then I might be erased.
私 消されてしまうかも
しれないものね
（ﾚﾅ）連中？
Those guys?
ウフフッ… じゃあね！
See you later.
（大石）綿流しの夜―
On Cotton Drifting night...
Tomitake-san
and Takano-san died.
富竹さんと鷹野さん
お亡くなりになったんですよ
（ﾚﾅ）“帰巣性とホームシック”…
Homing instincts
and homesickness?
Concerning Maggots and
Oyashiro-sama's Curse
ウワッ！
Ow...
What are you doing, Rena?
何やってんだよ？ レナ
私 最近
誰かに見張られてるみたいなの
It seems like I'm being
watched these days.
えっ？ まさか 警察？
By the cops?
それは分からないけど
I don't know, but it's been ever
since Cotton Drifting night.
綿流しの夜以降ずっと…
（圭一）どういうことだよ？
What do you mean?
連中は三四さんのスクラップ帳を
捜しているんだと思う
I think those guys are
after Miyo-san's scrapbook.
三四さんって…
Miyo-san...
あっ 鷹野さんのことか
You mean Takano-san?
Miyo Takano-san got killed.
鷹野三四さん… 殺されたんだって
ええっ？ いつ？
When?
綿流しの夜
私たちと会った あの直後に
On Cotton Drifting night
right after we met her.
Tomitake-san was also killed.
富竹さんも殺された
Tomitake-san too?
富竹さんも？
そんなの 誰も知らないぞ！
No one knows that!
That's because the police are
investigating without disclosing it.
警察が伏せて捜査してるからなの
（圭一）な… なんで？
W-Why?
I believe
it's because of her research.
多分 彼女の研究のせいだと思う
Through the research...
彼女は その研究の中で―
...she found out an important
secret about this village.
この村に関する
ある重要な秘密を知ってしまった
秘密って 何だよ？
What secret?
私は
三四さんのスクラップ帳を―
I only borrowed and read
a few of Miyo-san's scrapbooks...
ほんの数冊
借りて読んだだけなんだけど
あまりに突拍子もなくて…
...but it's so much, and I'm
in the process of verifying it.
検証してる段階なの
Verifying?
検証？
Car.
車！
（圭一）あっ…
Could that be
who's watching you?
もしかして
見張られてるって あれか？
（ﾚﾅ）多分…
Maybe.
ふだん 車なんか通らない道で
何度も見かけるから
I've seen it several times on a
street where cars rarely pass by.
Are they the ones who killed
Takano-san and Tomitake-san?
あいつらなのか？
鷹野さんたちを殺したのって
多分
Probably.
I'm sorry.
すまん
レナの味方になりたいのは本心だ
I want to help you, but I don't
understand the whole story.
でも 話が全然 見えない
Most likely...
恐らく 三四さんたちを
殺したのは雛見沢御三家
...the people who killed them are
Hinamizawa's three great families.
もっと はっきり言ってしまえば…
To be more specific, Mi-chan's
family, the Sonozaki family.
魅ぃちゃん家(ち)である園崎(そのざき)本家
まさか…
No way!
You also know about the serial
mysterious deaths, right?
圭一君も過去の連続怪死事件は
知ってるよね？
Yeah.
The consecutive
mysterious deaths...
その連続怪死事件は
オヤシロさま信仰を―
...seem to be aiming at reviving
religious belief of Oyashiro-sama.
復活させることを
目的としているものらしいの
でも どうして鷹野さんが
殺されなきゃいけないんだ？
But why did
Takano-san have to get killed?
That has to do with the important
secret the three great families...
それは 御三家が
太古から ずっと隠してきた―
重大な秘密に関係があるの
...have been hiding
since long ago.
それを暴かれると
オヤシロさまの神聖性が失われる
If that gets revealed...
...then the sacredness of
Oyashiro-sama will be lost.
Since those guys found out
Miyo-san got close to the truth...
だから 彼らは 三四さんの研究が
核心に近づいたことを知り―
消した
...they got rid of her.
What is the important secret?
重大な秘密って 何だ？
Well, I need more time
until I can verify it.
それは 私自身 確証を得るまで―
もう少し時間が欲しいの
分かった
I understand.
Don't tell anyone
about what I told you.
（ﾚﾅ）今話したことは
誰にも しゃべっちゃダメだよ
Mi-chan, Rika-chan,
and of course Satoko-chan.
魅ぃちゃんと梨花ちゃん
もちろん沙都子ちゃんにも…
ダメ
Yeah.
じゃ 私 もう行くね
Then I'm going to go now.
Rena!
レナ
We're friends, right?
私たち 仲間だよね？
（圭一）ああ
Yeah!
If the Sonozaki
family is involved...
園崎家が関わってるってことは
やっぱり 魅音も？
...then does that
mean Mion is as well?
アア… まさかな…
It can't be.
（男）にいちゃん すまんね
学校の帰りかい？
Sorry, kid. Are you on
your way home from school?
Yes, I am.
はい そうですけど
にいちゃんさ この道の途中で
女の子に会わんかったかいね？
Kid, on your way on
this road, did you see a girl?
She's wearing
a white hat and white clothes.
（男）白い帽子に
白い服を着た女の子なんよ
Oh, she also
has a purple ribbon on.
ああ 紫のリボンも着いとん
You didn't see her?
会わんかったかいねえ？
（圭一）いえ 会ってないです
No, I didn't.
ああ そんな深い意味はないんね
Oh, there's no serious
meaning behind it.
さっき 女の子を追い抜いたのによ
来たのが男の子だったから
Since we passed a girl,
but a boy came instead...
I-I see.
そうですか
ごめんな にいちゃん
I'm sorry, kid.
うちら ここら辺は
あんまり来んもんで―
Since we don't come
here often, we got lost.
道に迷うてもうてな
学校へ行くには
どうしたらいいんかい？
Do you know how
to get to the school?
The school?
学校ですか？
Those guys are after Rena...
あいつらがレナを…
When They Cry
レナ 話してくれ
Rena, please tell me.
鷹野さんが消されるほどの何が
スクラップ帳に書かれてるんだ？
What's written on the scrapbook
that led to Takano-san's murder?
簡単に言うと…
To be concise, if what's
written in the scrapbook is true...
このスクラップ帳に
書かれてあることが事実なら―
...then their god will
be looked down upon.
彼らの神が
おとしめられることになるの
Their god will
be looked down on?
（圭一）神をおとしめる？
（ﾚﾅ）そう
Yeah.
So those who are trying to revive
belief in Oyashiro-sama...
だから オヤシロさま信仰を―
復活させようと
している彼らにとって―
...had to keep it a secret.
そのことは 絶対 表沙汰に
してはいけないことだったの
Sorry, Rena. Can you say it
so that I can understand?
すまん レナ もう少し分かりやすく
言ってくれないか？
つまり オヤシロさまは
神さまじゃないってことなの
In other words,
Oyashiro-sama is not a god.
“神さまじゃない”？
Not a god?
オヤシロさまの教えって
いくつもあるけど
There are many teachings
from Oyashiro-sama...
その原点は たったひとつしかない
...but they are all
based on one thing.
That is not to leave
and not to let others in.
それは“中から出るな
外から入るな”というもの
To begin with,
why was Oyashiro-sama born?
そもそも オヤシロさまは
なぜ降臨したのか？
That's because demons emerged
from Onigafuchi Swamp...
それは “鬼ヶ淵の沼より
鬼が湧き出し―”
...and attacked the villagers.
“人々を襲ったから”なんだけど
実は この時点で解釈が違ってたの
From this point,
there was a misinterpretation.
鬼が湧き出して 襲ったんじゃない
The demons didn't emerge
and attack the villagers.
If one touched what emerged...
湧き出したものに やられると
人々を襲う鬼になるの
...then that person became
a demon who attacked people.
What emerged?
湧き出したもの？
寄生虫だよ
Parasites.
Parasites?
寄生虫？
（ﾚﾅ）そう
Yeah.
It's a bizarre, contagious disease
that emerged from the swamp.
（ﾚﾅ）
それは沼より発生した奇怪な伝染病
感染者を凶暴化させる奇怪な寄生虫
A bizarre parasite makes
the infected person insane.
Would it be easier to understand
if I refer to it as a virus?
ウイルスって言ったほうが
分かりやすいかな？
Y-Yeah, that explains
the legend well, but...
た… 確かに それだと
伝説をうまく説明できるけど
じゃ オヤシロさまってのは―
Then could Oyashiro-sama...
...be a doctor who came
from a foreign country?
ひょっとして
異国から来た医者とか？
I can't be certain...
正確には分からないけど
医者と呼べる存在
...but someone who can
be referred to as a doctor.
That person might have tried
to treat the contagious disease.
それが伝染病治療をしたんだろうね
But it wasn't treatment.
It was allopathy.
でも それは治療ではなく
対症療法でしかなかった
Allopathy?
対症療法？
（ﾚﾅ）当時は
それしか できなかったんだと思う
I think at that time,
that was all they could do.
And to prevent the damage from
spreading, they created rules.
そして 被害を拡大させないために
掟(おきて)を作った
それが“村から出てはいけない
外から入れてはいけない”だったの
"You can't leave the village,
and you can't let others in."
To not spread the infection, huh?
感染者を増やさないためか
It seems the parasites can
only survive in Hinamizawa...
寄生虫たちは
気候や風土の関係で―
この雛見沢の地でしか
生きられないらしいの
...due to
the temperature and climate.
When the infected person, the
host, tries to leave Hinamizawa...
（ﾚﾅ）宿主である感染者が
この地を離れようとすると―
...the parasites cause severe
symptoms to stop the departure.
強い症状を出して
それを妨害する
その妨害こそが いわゆる
オヤシロさまのたたりの正体
The interference is what
Oyashiro-sama's curse is about.
ちょっと待てよ レナ
昔なら ともかく―
Wait a second, Rena.
I don't know about the past...
...but it isn't uncommon for
people to leave or enter now.
今じゃ この村を
出入りしている人は珍しくないぞ
Yeah.
そう… それは 正に―
That is because things went
just as Oyashiro-sama planned.
オヤシロさまの もくろみどおりに
事が進んだからなんだよ
この村を長い間 封印してきたのは
寄生虫の害を弱めるため
The reason they sealed
the village so long...
...was to lessen
the danger of the parasites.
つまり 錯乱して
ほかの人間を襲ったりすれば―
In order words, if a person went
insane and attacked another...
...then that person was
killed along with the parasite.
その感染者は寄生虫と共に殺された
The strong parasite
that made people insane...
感染者を錯乱させてしまうような
強すぎる寄生虫もまた―
...was also killed
together with the host.
錯乱した宿主と共に殺された
As a result, only
the parasites and people...
その結果 寄生虫と人間は―
...who were compatible
with each other survived.
互いに相性がいい種だけが
残っていった
So you mean natural selection.
自然淘汰(しぜんとうた)ってわけか
This is the truth behind
the Oyashiro-sama legend...
これこそが
オヤシロさま伝説が伝える―
鬼と人の血が
混じり合ったことの真相
...passed down about how
demon and human blood mixed.
I see.
なるほどな
そして 最古の綿流しは―
And cotton drifting in the past...
錯乱した犠牲者の
臓腑(ぞうふ)を食らうというものだったの
...was to eat the intestines of
the people who became insane.
でも これも必要なことだった
But this was also necessary.
まさか ワクチンとか？
Was it for vaccination?
フフッ…
圭一君は やっぱり頭がいいね
You're smart, just as I thought.
In reality, it wasn't that barbaric,
but they created vaccines...
実際は
そんなに野蛮なものじゃなくて―
死んだ犠牲者から
ワクチンを作り出し―
村人の
抵抗力を高めていったらしいけど
...from those who died
to bolster the villagers' resistance.
なんだか
サイエンスな感じがして―
It sounds so scientific
that it's interesting.
ちょっと面白い話だな
（ﾚﾅ）うん…
Yeah...
But for those who worship
Oyashiro-sama as a god...
でも オヤシロさまを神として
あがめる人たちにとっては―
これは とても不愉快な説
...this theory can be disturbing.
True...
確かに もし この伝染病の
病原体を特定して―
If the pathogen of this
contagious disease was found...
...and announced to the public,
the belief will be ruined.
世間に
発表されるようなことがあれば―
信仰は破綻してしまうな
オヤシロさまの狂信者たちにとって
神の力を復活させるということは
If Oyashiro-sama's
fanatical organization...
...is going to revive
their god's power...
つまり 害の極めて強い寄生虫を
復活させるということ
...that means they'll revive
a highly dangerous parasite.
C-Could it be that
the goal of the organization...
も… もしかして
狂信者どもの目的は―
...is to spread the ancient
parasite all over Hinamizawa?
その太古の寄生虫を
雛見沢中に ばらまくことなのか？
I think so.
多分 “オヤシロさまの復活”
それがヤツらの最終目的
The revival of Oyashiro-sama.
That's their ultimate goal.
そ… それって
細菌テロっていわないか？
D-Don't you call
that bioterrorism?
Yeah.
うん…
（圭一）なあ レナ
Hey, Rena, is the Sonozaki
family behind all this?
黒幕は園崎家なのか？
魅音も関係があるってのか？
Is Mion also involved?
I don't know if she or Rika-chan,
who are part of those families...
御三家である
魅ぃちゃんや梨花ちゃんが―
直接 関係しているか分からない
...are directly involved.
But even if they weren't,
if they hear about it...
けど…
もし 無関係だったとしても―
耳に入れることで 危険に
巻き込んでしまうかもしれない
...they might be in danger.
くそ 鷹野さんめ！
Damn that Takano-san!
How dare she
leave such a mess.
とんでもない置き土産を
残してくれたな
But I'm glad that
you're on my side.
でも 圭一君が味方で良かったよ
（圭一）当たり前だろう！
Of course!
We're friends, aren't we?
仲間なんだからな！
（ﾚﾅ）うん
Yeah.
Thank you.
（ﾚﾅ）ありがとう
（生徒たち）２番！
Number two!
Correct. Well then...
正解！ それじゃ…
So, Mion, it's not that way.
だから 魅音 そうじゃなくて―
You have to calculate it this way.
こっちで計算しなきゃダメなんだよ
（魅音）むぅ～！
Gosh, it's so tedious!
（魅音）ああ もう 面倒くさいな
（ﾚﾅ）あっ…
（車の音）
（圭一）ほい 最初から
Okay, from the beginning.
（魅音）うん？ えっと…
Um...
Oh, I get it!
あっ 分かった分かった！
（圭一）だから 違うって！
It's wrong!
- Huh?
- Don't "huh" me!
（魅音）え～っ？
（圭一）“え～っ”じゃねえよ！
Staff Room
（知恵）
では よろしくお願いします
Staff Room
I'll leave it to you.
（男）はい
こちらこそ よろしくお願いします
Yes, we'll take care of it.
あっ あと これ ウチの事務屋から
渡すように言われましたんが
Oh, I was also told
to hand this to you.
はい
Okay.
I will show you the way.
では ご案内しますので
（男）
いや しっかし 暑いこってすな
It sure is hot.
I know.
（知恵）ホントですね
（知恵）でも
暑い日はカレーが おいしいですよ
But on hot days, curry is good.
（男）オッ… うんですかい
Oh, really?
Okokogi Landscapers
（音声ｶﾞｲﾀﾞﾝｽ）お客さまが
おかけになった電話番号は―
The number you have
dialed is not in service.
現在 使われておりません
（ﾚﾅ）あっ…
Please check
the number and try again.
番号をお確かめのうえ
もう一度 おかけ直し…
お客さまが
おかけになった電話番号は―
The number you have
dialed is not in service.
現在 使われておりません
Okokogi Landscapers
The number you have
dialed is not in service.
As I thought, they're...
やっぱり あいつら…
（知恵）竜宮さんの早退を
聞いてる人は いませんか？
Did anyone hear about
Ryugu-san leaving early?
Mi...
It's worrisome that
she left without telling anyone.
黙って帰っちゃうなんて
困りましたね
Something bothers me.
なんだか イヤな予感がするぜ
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
The blood that oozes out
is the memory of the past.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
にじみだす血は 過去への記憶
What you noticed
is the severity of the sin.
気づいたのは 罪の重さ
そこにあるのは 決着の未来
What is there
is the decisive future.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 4: EARTH INVASION.
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 04: EARTH INVASION
"Atonement" Chapter,
Episode 4: EARTH INVASION.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Atonement" Chapter -
Episode 04: EARTH INVASION
Can you believe it?